Welcome to Road to the Draft powered by
[music] Microsoft Copilot. In today's
episode, senior writer and editor Scott
Smith discusses two possible trade
scenarios [music] and highlights an
inside linebacker and edge rusher to
keep an eye on.
>> [music]
>> Thank you, Casey. [music]
We've come pretty far down this Road to
the Draft, but today we're going to slam
it into reverse.
>> [music]
>> And I don't mean we're going to go back
down the road we've already covered or
go back in time. What I do mean is we're
going to talk about the possibility of
the Buccaneers trading back in the first
round. Now, the concept for the
Buccaneers is pretty obvious. You Let's
say you're looking for you're hoping to
land maybe an edge rusher or an off-ball
linebacker or maybe even a certain tight
end from Oregon and your pick is coming
up at 15 and you think there's five or
six guys that we like and we can move
down, couple of them will still be
available and we'll pick up some draft
assets in that process. And so, [music]
the the issue, of course, anytime you
talk about trading down is you have to
find a dance partner. And there's no
guarantee that will happen, but we came
up with a couple ideas that we thought
were possible and that's the Pittsburgh
Steelers at 21 and the Chiefs at 29. And
in the upcoming segment, we'll explain
why that's the case. But for the
Buccaneers, these are two that we're
targeting and the idea, of course, again
is to get some extra draft capital and
still get your guy. And I actually
looked at some trades recent trades. I
couldn't find that one that was exactly
15 to 21, but there's been some similar
trades in recent years that could give
us an idea of what the Buccaneers could
get back. And for instance, Minnesota
traded up with Jacksonville from 23 to
17 in 2024 and they got a fifth that
year and a third and a fourth the next
year, which added together is a the
equivalent of the 74th pick, which is a
high third-rounder. So, you're looking
at an extra high third-round pick, which
would be very valuable. Uh in 2021, the
Jets traded up with Minnesota from 23 to
14. They got two third round picks back
and gave back a fourth, so that's a
pretty good haul as well. And then
Houston and Cleveland in '17, Houston
went from 25 to 12 and got an
a 2018 first-round pick and uh that's a
little bit more of a leap and maybe more
of what we're talking about with this
move, but it's important because that
was for Deshaun Watson. And when teams
are trading up to get a quarterback and
the other team knows it, they usually
pay a little bit more of a premium. So,
after going through all this, we'll take
a look at why the Buccaneers could
potentially trade with one of these two
teams.
Okay, now, why do we choose these two
teams, Pittsburgh and Kansas City?
>> Well, we asked Copilot to help us out
with that and kind of go through what
they've done during their off-season and
why that might make them a candidate to
trade up for the Buccaneers. So, we
start with Pittsburgh at number 21. Uh
biggest thing Pittsburgh probably did
was signing Michael Pittman or actually
trading for Michael Pittman Jr. That
really solves their probably biggest
need on offense [music]
uh other than what we're going to
discuss in a moment. They also got a
running back. Obviously, we know they
got a former Buccaneer Jamel Dean
[music] and Jaquan Brisker from the
Bears, so that helped out the secondary.
Uh but if you look down here, remaining
positional needs, quarterback. That
jumps out. Will Aaron Rodgers come back
for one season?
Probably, maybe, but even if he does,
that's probably a one-season solution.
And uh Mason Rudolph and Will Howard
probably not long-term starters. So,
this is one of the few teams in the
second half of the draft that might
actually be angling for a quarterback.
And there's been some buzz lately about
Ty Simpson from Alabama. Why is this
important for them to move up to 15?
Because the New York Jets, another team
that have been linked at possibly taking
quarterback like Ty Simpson in the first
round and they've already had their pick
at number two, so they can add a
defensive player. They are picking 16.
The Bucks are in the perfect position to
trade up for that. So, that's why you
think possibly the Pittsburgh Steelers
might be motivated to trade up a little
bit, maybe give up a third-round pick.
[music] Uh now we come to the Kansas
City Chiefs who got this pick number 29
in the trade. What they've done in free
agency, their big move, of course, was
to sign Kenneth Walker. They had one of
the roughest white running back rooms in
the league last year, especially in
terms of explosive plays, but they
totally solved that problem. They did
sign a safety. They're probably still
looking for some help in the secondary,
though. As you can see here, the
remaining positional [music] needs. I
would highlight two of these things,
cornerback and offensive tackle. There's
a very real possibility that a run could
develop, let's say with offensive
tackles. There's a [music] good There's
three or four really highly regarded
offensive tackles in this draft, but
after that, it kind of falls off and
it's not a great draft to get in tackle
[music] on day two. If there's an early
run on offensive tackles and the and the
Chiefs really like one, say Monroe
Freeling. A lot of teams could be
motivated to move up to number 15 to get
their hands on what maybe is considered
last blue-chip [music] offensive tackle.
So, that's why we think these two teams
have a possibility. Now, if [music]
you're talking about trading up from 29
to 15, that's a bigger jump than the
Pittsburgh one and I think you're
probably looking at at least a
second-round pick, if not a first-round
pick the next [music] year.
Well, okay, let's talk a little bit
about why the Bucks might be confident
in moving back a bit in the
>> first round and still landing a player
they very much covet. First, we're going
to look at C.J. Allen, the Georgia
off-ball linebacker. Maybe the second
guy off the board at that position after
Sonny Styles from Ohio State. He's got
Lavonte David type of size at 6'1 and
230. Uh love Lavonte David, obviously.
Uh he wore the green dot on his helmet.
He's got good sideline-to-sideline range
and very critically is very good in
coverage, which is something the
Buccaneers are emphasizing to improve at
the linebacker position in the middle of
defense this year. So, that's an
intriguing player. Now, if we're talking
about moving all the way back to 29,
what you're probably counting on is
depth at the outside linebacker
position. And one guy who we've seen his
stock raise quite a bit uh since the
combine is Zion Young of Missouri. You
generally considered early in the
process as a second-round pick, he's
very much moved into the bottom of the
first round territory in a lot of mock
drafts you see. As you can see, the
Buccaneers want to get bigger. He's 6'6,
262 lb. Very much a relentless worker.
Also good against the run, can set the
edge, can convert speed to power, so he
can bull rush through guys. Maybe not
the quickest first step off the line and
that's why he's not a top 15 [music]
pick probably in most mock drafts, but
you're seeing him late in the second
round. If the Buccaneers feel confident
that there are going to be a number of
players like Zion Young, maybe Cashius
Howel, uh T.J. Parker, guys like that
still available, at least one or two of
them at pick number 29, they could feel
comfortable moving that far back in the
draft. That's going to do it for us on
this edition of Road to the Draft
powered by Copilot. We are officially
less than a month away from the NFL
Draft and we're going to be here with
you all the way up until it, so we'll
see you next time.
>> [music]